# The Story of VoxWeave
VoxWeave takes inspiration from the
original Python project while embracing
the safety guarantees and performance
profile of Rust. It demonstrates
how text normalization, subtitle generation,
and speech synthesis can be
implemented in a modular, test-driven
manner. ## Text Normalisation The
pipeline collapses stray whitespace, preserves
intentional paragraph breaks, and optionally
replaces single newlines with spaces.
This ensures the audiobook experience
mirrors natural narration instead of
literal line-by-line reading. ## Subtitle
Timing Subtitle segments can follow
sentences or fixed word counts.
This example uses grouped words
so that the resulting SRT
file remains readable, even when
paired with rapid narration. ##
Audio Output When the espeak
engine is available, VoxWeave writes
a WAV file to disk.
For environments without audio backends,
the `--mock` flag produces a
textual representation that keeps integration
tests fast and deterministic. ##
Conclusion Porting complex Python applications
to Rust is achievable with
steady iteration, thoughtful boundary seams,
and comprehensive tests. VoxWeave showcases
these techniques in a practical,
audio-focused context.